# VISHAL SRIVASTAVA

304 B Block Scrum Utkarsh Society, Pune Email- vishalsrivastava.official@gmail.com Mobile- :+91 9044480338, +91 7905761485

## **SUMMARY**

Award-winning developer with 3.4+ years of Full Stack Developer experience in HTML, CSS, Java Script, Angular, Vue.js, Nuxt.js framework, Java and its framework like Hibernate, Spring Security, Spring Boot REST API. My main interests are object-oriented and user-centered design. Highly accomplished in manipulating visual hierarchy. A regular contributor to product enhancement. A trainer who successfully motivated a group of young developers into getting highest accolades for their recent endeavors.

## **EXPERIENCE**

- 3.4+ Years of experience as Full Stack Developer.
- Expert in Java and its framework like Spring Boot etc.
- Expert in developing Web-based user interfaces.
- Working experience as an Angular Developer for CITI Bank client and Fast App BPM Project.
- Collaborated closely with the team to support projects during all phases of delivery.
- Built websites and apps that are responsive and usable.
- Monitored website performance and rectifying front-end-related issues.
- Knowledge in AWS systems for storing and hosting the services.
- Ability to work in fast-paced environment.
- Experience in building REST API using Spring Boot.
- Understanding of web services technologies such as **REST**, **JSON** and **HTTP** etc.
- Maintained an organized workflow using a project management tool (like GitHub, Redmine, JIRA).
- Tested to identify bugs and technical issues before and after deploying.
- Documented bug reports, tickets, and any code changes.

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

**Employer: Dassault Systemes** 

Address: Pune

Period: Jan 2020- Present

Job title: Software Development Engineer

## **Job Responsibilities:**

- To work with the UI and Backend department in designing and developing the websites using Vue.js and Java Framework.
- To develop REST APIs using Spring Boot Framework for the front end.
- To follow responsive user interface design principles and ensured the technical feasibility of these User Interface designs for the best user experience possible.
- To create the test cases for the unit test of dynamic functionalities.
- Management of project repository using version control tool Gitlab & Redmine.
- To Troubleshoot and fix any frontend issues and tests the product for multi-device and cross-browser capability.
- To Ensure accuracy and synchrony in both the frontend and backend development at all stages of the product development.
- Contribution in the design mockups for the best user experience.
- To interact with product owners to get the requirements of the next Sprint.

**Employer: Infosys Limited** 

Address: Rajiv Gandhi IT Park, Chandigarh - 160101

Period: March 2017- December 2019

Job title: Senior Systems Engineer

## **Job Responsibilities:**

• To follow the SDLC model & Agile Methodology for product development.

- To work with the user interface department in designing and developing the websites using Angular Framework.
- Management of project repository using version control tool GIT & Bit bucket.
- To ensure accuracy and synchrony in both the frontend and backend development at all stages of the product development.
- Contribution in the design mockups for the best user experience.

## **PROJECTS:**

# • 3D Experience Products platform

## **Current Project**

Dassault Systemes developed many products like Solidworks, CATIA and many more. We are working on enterprise experiences of these products.

## • Citi Bank Advice Generation System

#### 2.9 Years

Citi Bank AGS is the major product for employees of Citi Bank to generate, hold, reject, print the Advices for the clients. This Application built in Angular 5 framework along with Bootstrap, Material Design etc. My role in this project is Web Developer.

## **ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS**

Year	Institute / University / Board	Percentage	Degree
2012-16	Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam University (AKTU)	79.10	B.Tech. (CS)
2011	CBSE	77.6	Intermediate
2009	CBSE	83.8	High School

## **SKILLS**

Languages:	JavaScript, SQL, Java	
Frameworks:	Spring Boot, Angular, Bootstrap, Selenium, Vue.js, Nuxt, Node.js	
Tools:	JIRA, GIT, Android Studio, Eclipse	
DBMS:	SQL, Mongo DB	
Basics	Java Core, Data Structures & Algorithms	
Operating Systems:	Microsoft Windows	

# **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**

- > 3 Times INSTA Award winner in Infosys Ltd for outstanding performance in my Team.
- Good Academic Record.

Date: 30-June-2020 Signature: Vishal Srivastava